[{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"1. It's not the mouth or tongue, but cholinergic polymodal chemosensory cells in this structure unusually recognize bitter taste. Non-specific inflammation of this structure can be caused by Mycoplasma hominis. Increased anterior compartment descent is a sign of hypermobility of this structure, which is treated with a PV sling. The opening of this structure is respectively either too dorsal or too ventral in epispadias and hypospadias. The deep, perineal branch of the pudendal nerve innervates the external sphincter controlling access to this structure. A balloon inflated with water lies at the tip of a device named for Foley, which is initially inserted into this structure. This structure is divided into spongy, membranous, and prostatic portions in men, who often experience a compression of this structure due to an enlarged prostate. Because this structure is much shorter in women than men, women experience more UTIs. For 10 points, name this tube through which both semen and urine pass in men. ","answer":"ANSWER: urethra <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"2. The third movement of a cantata from this country is often omitted or revised because its long text is recited, not sung, by a narrator; that movement also quotes this country’s national anthem. A composer born in this country cast male soprano Michael Maniaci to play Little Green in his Pulitzer-winning opera based on a legend from this country. Rousseau’s Dictionnaire de musique contained a theme from this country with one crucial pitch mis-notated; Carl Maria von Weber introduced that theme with “drums and pipes” in his incidental music for a play adapted by Friedrich Schiller. That theme from this country is introduced by a flute in the scherzo of Paul Hindemith’s Symphonic Metamorphosis. Textural densities, dynamics, durations, tempos, and sounds were determined by consulting charts with reference to a book from this country when composing the indeterminate piece Music of Changes. For 10 points, John Cage composed using the 64 hexagrams of the I Ching, a book from what country? ","answer":"ANSWER: People’s Republic of China [or Zhōnghuá Rénmín Gònghéguó] <Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"3. John de Figueiredo and Emerson Tiller advanced the “efficiency hypothesis” to explain the expansion of the number of holders of this position from an original number of thirteen to over 300 by the 1960s. In research on holders of this position, Paul Collins has highlighted a distinction between the “information” and “affected groups” hypotheses about how they process outside information. In a 2018 working paper, Elliott Ash, Daniel Chen, and Suresh Naidu concluded that holders of this position had been influenced by attending a “boot camp” conducted by the George Mason economist Henry Manne. The approximately 850 holders of this position serve “during good behavior” and are aided by “magistrates” who serve eight-year terms. Unlike their counterparts at the state level, holders of this position work under the restrictive Twombly/Iqbal pleading standards. For 10 points, name this position whose holders serve under Article III in the federal district and appellate courts. ","answer":"ANSWER: federal judges [accept answers indicating federal judiciary or United States or federal district court judges or United States or federal appellate court judges; do not accept or prompt on “(United States Supreme Court) Justice(s)” or similar answers mentioning or indicating “Supreme Court” or “Justice(s)”] <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"4. On a bus ride back home, the narrator of this novel observes a man he originally worries may be a homosexual reading The Charterhouse of Parma. This novel's narrator details the difference between regular places and \"certified\" places and also provides definitions for his concepts of repetition and malaise. Near the end of this novel, the narrator concludes, \"Nothing remains but desire.\" The protagonist of this novel, who was wounded in the Korean War, is injured in a hit-and-run from an elderly Ohio driver while heading to the beach with his secretary and love interest Sharon Kincaid. The narrator of this novel goes on a trip to Chicago with his cousin Kate Cutrer, who had recently attempted suicide. For 10 points, name this novel about the stockbroker Binx Bolling, a New Orleans-based frequenter of films by Walker Percy. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Moviegoer <American Literature> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 3/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 3 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"5. This country’s first president claimed descent from a resistance leader who built the first African army outfitted exclusively with firearms by sending blacksmiths to infiltrate an arsenal at Saint-Louis. A president of this country, who claimed to be the grandson of the Wassoulou Empire founder Samori, jailed dissidents in the deadly Camp Boiro. Because this country’s government supported insurgents in a neighboring country fighting for the PAIGC, Portuguese soldiers invaded this country to trigger a coup in Operation Green Sea. This country achieved independence in 1958, two years before the rest of French Africa, by voting “No” in a referendum to receive economic aid and integration with France. Stokely Carmichael died in this country, where he chose his new surname in honor of its president, Sekou Toure. For 10 points, name this former French colony on the coast of West Africa which is governed from the port city of Conakry. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of Guinea <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"6. This man's translator Richard Zenith noted how, as a teenager in Durban, South Africa, he designed elaborate English-language newspapers filled with fake events. This author correctly prophesied his posthumous legacy in the line \"roots may be hidden in the ground / But their flowers flower in the open air for all to see\" in his poem \"If I Die Young.\" A character created by this author dies in his mid-twenties from tuberculous after penning lines such as, \"I thank God I'm not good.\" Margaret Jull Costa's \"complete\" edition of this poet's seminal collection is ordered chronologically, opening with a poem that declares, \"My soul is a hidden orchestra.\" Many of the earliest poems in Jull's editions are purportedly by Vicente Guedes, whereas others are ascribed to a doctor named Ricardo Reis. For 10 points, name this Portuguese poet of The Book of Disquiet, known for his heteronyms. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fernando Pessoa [or Fernando António Nogueira Pessoa; accept Ricardo Reis or Vicente Guedes before mentioned; or Alberto Caeiro; or Bernardo Soares] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"7. This text calls Adam “the first apothecary” in a section that describes the jarring discovery of a stocking-mill in the Swiss mountains. While reading an obituary, this text’s author is struck by an apparent tangent about how only bad people dislike the company of children, which he takes as a barbed attack on him. The author of this text tries to avoid a large dog running at him by jumping over it at the last second; after his plan fails, he is knocked out and upon waking is overcome by the night sky and stars. This posthumously published text defends the author against claims he is an “unnatural” father and describes how he has left the “futile ideas” of the salons for the beauty of Nature. Patterned after Montaigne’s Essays, this text includes nine finished sections and an unfinished tenth section set on the fiftieth anniversary of the day the author met Madame Warens. For 10 points, name this contemplative work about Jean-Jacques Rousseau’s strolls around Paris. ","answer":"ANSWER: Reveries of the Solitary Walker [or Reveries of the Solitary Walker or Reveries of a Solitary Walker or Les Rêveries du promeneur solitaire] <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"8. A Bible named for this city was the first to be published in Ladino. Joseph Saralvo supposedly circumcised 800 adults in this city before the Roman Inquisition burned him at the stake, and all of this city's Jews would have been expelled following a 1570 earthquake if they didn't receive protection from its ruler, a patron of Torquato Tasso. A son of Lucrezia Borgia who ruled this city welcomed the rich merchant Samuel Abravanel following the merchant's expulsion from Naples. A medieval power struggle between the Salinguerra and Adelardi families in this university city and birthplace of Savonarola gave way to rule by a family that were also Dukes of Reggio and Modena. A woman born here who moved to Mantua patronized artists such as Titian and was named Isabella. For 10 points, name this Italian city northeast of Bologna, once ruled by the Este family. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ferrara <World History> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 4/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 4 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"9. One character in this opera sings a march-like dotted eighth-sixteenth theme punctuated by a high half note in his aria “Me protegge, me difende”; that march theme is imitated in another character’s extended aside in which she waits for a man’s return. The male lead of this opera is the only character who sings an uninterrupted double aria, or cavatina-cabaletta aria. This opera’s title character sings an aria whose violin parts include a low G, which must be adjusted for that aria’s common transposition down to F major, a change perpetuated since its premiere by Giuditta Pasta. The composer of this opera frequently collaborated with its librettist, Felice Romani. Maria Callas performed an aria from this opera eighty-nine times in concert during the postwar bel canto revival; that aria was “Casta Diva.” Ending with Pollione and the title priestess’s self-immolation in a Druid temple, for 10 points, name this opera by Vincenzo Bellini. ","answer":"ANSWER: Norma <Other Fine Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"0. John Renshaw Carson devised a variation of this operation so that the underlying step function yields a constant for all values of a certain coefficient whenever this operation is used. One method of calculating the inverse of this operation considers whether the sums of two series have first-order or second-order poles; that partial fraction expansion method. The range of this operation can be extended to the reals using the Heaviside function. Because this transform turns convolution into multiplication, it is often used to study linear time-invariant systems and solve differential equations. The integral from 0 to infinity of “f of t, times e to the negative s t” defines, for 10 points, what “transform” that maps a function from a time domain to the s-domain? ","answer":"ANSWER: Laplace transform <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"1. The protagonist of this novel considers himself caught between the \"stirrup and the ground\" and is brought down by a “big-breasted” character who conducts a séance with Old Crow. Near the end of this novel, a girl talks with a priest about wanting to be damned like her intimacy-hating husband, a man who told her \"God damn you, you little bitch, why can't you go back home forever and let me be\" on a vinyl record. That same waitress in this novel notices that Spicer has left a Kolley Kibber card that does not bear his likeness, ruining a man’s alibi. The antihero of this novel jumps off a cliff after failing to throw vitriol in the face of his wife. It opens with Fred Hale trying to escape from being killed among the Whitsun crowd at the title location. For 10 points, Rose is married to the gangster Pinkie Brown to keep her from testifying against him in what Graham Greene novel titled for a type of candy at an English seaside resort? ","answer":"ANSWER: Brighton Rock <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"2. At an American Physical Society meeting, Steven Weinberg admitted to “being naughty” in using the approach of a group of this name in his book To Understand the World. A writer criticizing that group calls for using “technical history” to overcome “abridgements” common in their work. Samuel Johnson once said that the first member of a faction of this name “was the devil.” A group with this name “studies the past with reference to the present” and views the voice of posterity as the “voice of God” according to a critique viewed as targeting G. M. Trevelyan and Thomas Babington Macaulay. That group’s Interpretation of History was criticized by Herbert Butterfield for arguing that history moves inexorably towards progress. A faction led by the 1 st Earl of Shaftesbury known as the Country Party later took this name and tried to pass three Exclusion Bills against the future James II. For 10 points, give this name of the pro-Parliament English group that opposed the Tories. ","answer":"ANSWER: Whigs [or Whig historians] <European History> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 5/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 5 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"3. In her best-known book, Islamic scholar Amina Wadud refutes “three common justifications” for this practice as having no basis in the Qur’an. Hind bint Utbah, the mother of Muawiya I, is often dubiously accused of partaking in the forbidden ijtima variety of this practice, which dates back to pre-Islamic Arabia. According to the Sahih al-Bukhari, ‘Aisha narrated a story about an orphan girl and her date palm to explain why the stipulation “if you fear that you cannot act equitably towards orphans” appears in the verse of the Qur’an sanctioning this practice. “What your right hands possess” is offered an alternative to engaging in this practice according to the verse 3 of the Sura an-Nisāʼ, which states that only if all participants are treated justly can it be carried out with “two or three or four” people. To secure alliances, Muhammad engaged in this practice with several widows and two women named Zainab. For 10 points, name this practice of having more than one spouse at once. ","answer":"ANSWER: polygamy [or polgyny; or polyandry; accept answers suggesting having more than one spouse before “spouse” is read; or plural marriages; prompt on marriage or nikah before “spouse” is read] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"4. This element is added ortho to a direct metalation group such as a methoxy group or a tertiary amine in directed ortho metalation, which encourages an electrophilic aromatic substitution with a strong preference for an ipso substitution at this element’s position. In contrast to previously proposed radical and single electron transfer mechanisms, Wittig proposed the formation of an “ate-complex” intermediate for a reaction in which this element is exchanged for a halogen. A reagent containing this metal catalyzes a 1,2 rearrangement in which an ether’s R group trades places with the neighboring carbon’s hydrogen to form an alcohol. This element causes copper to have a slightly negative charge in a soft nucleophilic reagent used to perform 1,4 additions. Gilman reagents contain copper and this metal, which is bound to a tert-butyl group in a very strong base. The small size of this element’s cation gives it greater polarizing strength than other alkali metal cations. For 10 points, name this lightest metal on the periodic table. ","answer":"ANSWER: lithium [or Li] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"5. An object used for this activity that belonged to Meryl Streep was included in the first-ever showing of an artist’s paintings of this subject, which was organized by Helen A. Cooper at the Yale University Art Gallery. Because of an artist’s very-precise perspective drawings, 7:20 p.m. has been calculated as the time setting for a painting of this activity whose right-hand side is dominated by a giant stone pillar. An artist painted himself performing this activity while using an object named for his sister, Josie, in the middle distance of a canvas that is alternately titled for a “champion” of this sport. In the largest of an artist’s painting of this subject, two muscular men wearing blue bandanas compete in this activity; that painting is The Biglin Brothers Turning the Stake. The Pennsylvania Railroad Connecting Bridge appears in the far background of a painting of this activity. For 10 points, a painting by Thomas Eakins shows his friend Max Schmitt performing what athletic activity on the Schuylkill River? ","answer":"ANSWER: rowing [or sculling; prompt on boating; prompt on racing] <Painting and Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"4. For 10 points, name this first major federal law against racial discrimination passed in the U.S. since Reconstruction. ","answer":"ANSWER: Civil Rights Act of 1957 [prompt on Civil Rights Act] <American History> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 6/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 6 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"7. In 2019, Sayeef Salahuddin’s research group reported observation of negative values of this quantity. When measuring this quantity at high frequency for a MOSFET, it will often be reduced to its “deep depletion” value because the inversion layer does not have a chance to grow. This quantity is multiplied by a factor of one plus the voltage gain in the Miller effect, which limits the bandwidth of amplifiers. This quantity equals 4 pi times the permittivity of free space divided by the difference of the inverses of the two radii for two concentric spheres in a vacuum. One form of impedance equals one over the imaginary unit times frequency times this quantity. This quantity equals permittivity times area divided by distance for two parallel metal plates. For 10 points, name this quantity equal to the ratio of stored charge to voltage, which is measured in farads. ","answer":"ANSWER: capacitance <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"8. Letters saved by this man’s son-in-law Rudolf Kayser were used to make a font out of his handwriting for a 2015 exhibit at the Sigmund Freud Museum. Alice Calaprice wrote an “encyclopedia” named for this man which dispels biographer Abraham Pais's claim this man \"might as well have gone fishing\" after a certain point in his career, and addresses theories that the Serbian mathematician Mileva Marić made significant contributions to his work. Disney CEO Bob Iger demanded that Psychological Science retract a 2007 paper proving that a product named for this person did not benefit toddlers. This man lends his name to an @Home distributed computing software package that crunches data from LIGO. Along with Leo Szilard, he wrote a letter to FDR advocating for the creation of the Manhattan Project. For 10 points, name this physicist who formulated the Theory of Relativity. ","answer":"ANSWER: Albert Einstein [accept Baby Einstein] <Other Academic> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"9. H. A. Müller studied the vases produced for this event to come up with an order of festivities during it. The most important object in this event was brought from the Cerameicus, placed on a ship's mast, and then transported over land by special machine. One version of this festival featured male beauty contests and the pyrrhic war dance rather than a ceremony involving a peplus. Starting in the time of Hipparchus, rhapsodists began reciting praise songs to Harmodius during this festival, which is depicted on the inner frieze of the Parthenon. Nine months prior to this event, two young women were selected to live on the Acropolis and weave a new robe for a statue central to this festival. Every four years, people outside of Attica were invited to this event to partake in musical and athletic contests, including a noted torch race. For 10 points, name this festival whose name derives from the patron deity of Athens. ","answer":"ANSWER: Panathenaea [or Athenaea; or Greater Panathenaea; or Lesser Panathenaea] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"0. The author of this poem had earlier used its title for a poem that recalls how “heat was happy” and “flowers jumped / Like small goats” as the speaker walked to “where the river / Ran over stones.” This poem observes that “The lowly worm climbs up a winding stair” after wondering how “Light takes the Tree.” Besides reading the book Céline and His Vision, the narrator reads the opening lines of this poem from the collection Words for the Wind in the frame story of Kurt Vonnegut’s Slaughterhouse Five. The phrase “Great Nature has another thing to do / To you and me” appears in this poem, which exclaims “God bless the Ground! I shall walk softly there.” This poem repeats the line “I learn by going where I have to go.” For 10 points, the speaker declares “I wake to sleep and take” the title action “slow” in what Theodore Roethke poem? ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Waking” <World/Other Literature> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 7/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 7 Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Name this mystical Sufi order. King Idris, a chief of this order, ruled Libya for 18 years before he was overthrown in 1969 by Muammar Gaddafi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Senoussi Order [or Senoussi Movement] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Mussolini’s government used this two-word expression to refer to the Libyan coast, where it settled 100,000 Italian peasants. This phrase evoked Italian irredentist ambitions to dominate the Mediterranean, which they called “Mare Nostrum.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the Fourth Shore [or la Quarta Sponda] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] To enlarge its colonial empire, Fascist Italy also conquered this African empire, which had defeated Italy in the earlier Battle of Adowa. Italy deposed this empire’s ruler, Haile Selassie. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ethiopian Empire [or Abyssinia] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The relationship between itching and scratching is held to be conceptual, not inferential, according to the “criterial solution” to this problem, which J. S. Mill solved using analogical inference. ","answer":"ANSWER: problem of other minds "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] In this Platonic dialogue about the nature of rhetoric, Callicles admits that scratching, like receptive homosexuality, is performed merely to satisfy appetitive needs. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gorgias "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Against the argument that scratching merely satisfies a physical need, Sherri Irvin has argued that it can be studied in this branch of philosophy concerned with the nature of art and beauty. ","answer":"ANSWER: aesthetics <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Identify this poem that begins by claiming that “To sing of Wars, of Captaines, and of King\" are “too superior things” for the author’s “poor pen,” in reference to the following collection’s lengthy poem about the Four Monarchies. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Prologue” of The Tenth Muse Lately Sprung Up in America [or Anne Bradstreet’s “The Prologue”; prompt on “The Prologue” alone or descriptive answers like the first poem of The Tenth Muse Lately Sprung Up in America] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The image of “glistering gold” at the end of Bradstreet’s prologue is echoed later in the collection by the reference to “whole Mines of gold” in a poem addressed to this “dear and loving” person. ","answer":"ANSWER: Anne Bradstreet’s husband [or Simon Bradstreet] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The line “Give wholsome Parsley wreath, I aske no Bayes” from “The Prologue” is referenced by the title of the section on Bradstreet in this Elaine Showalter book, which takes its title from a 1917 short story and celebrates “American Women Writers from Anne Bradstreet to Annie Proulx.” ","answer":"ANSWER: A Jury of Her Peers <American Literature> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 8/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 8 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Name this electromagnetic radiation given off by all objects at a rate which varies with their temperature. ","answer":"ANSWER: blackbody radiation [or cavity radiation; prompt on “thermal radiation”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Wilhelm Wien showed that the spectral blackbody energy density for a given wavelength and temperature is proportional to this power of the temperature, not counting the exponential factor in the denominator. ","answer":"ANSWER: negative five "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] This scientist provided experimental support for Wien’s earlier exponential law with measurements of infrared emission from 1 to 8 microns. He lends his name to the spectral lines of hydrogen caused by an electron jumping down to the n = 3 shell. ","answer":"ANSWER: Friedrich Paschen <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Name these pedagogical musical pieces, which Szymanowska published in a collection alongside her Preludes. ","answer":"ANSWER: études [prompt on “study”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] This Italian composer of many piano sonatas wrote and arranged pieces for Art of Playing the Pianoforte, one of the first treatises to specifically address piano instead of harpsichord or clavichord. ","answer":"ANSWER: Muzio Clementi "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Robert Schumann used his characters of Florestan and Eusebius to critique this composer’s études’ lack of fantasy and inability to keep students’ attention. This Austrian composer and student of Clementi wrote the wildly popular A Complete Theoretical and Practical Course of Instruction on the Art of Playing the Piano Forte. ","answer":"ANSWER: Johann Nepomuk Hummel <Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Identify these cells named for an early 20th century Spanish neuroscientist, which serve as pacemakers by generating a basal electrical rhythm in the stomach and intestines. ","answer":"ANSWER: myenteric interstitial cells of Cajal [or ICC-MY; prompt on interstitial cells; prompt on cells of Cajal] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The basal electrical rhythm generated by ICCs coordinates this rhythmic contraction and relaxation of smooth muscles that propels food down the gastrointestinal tract. ","answer":"ANSWER: peristalsis "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The channel anoctamin-1, which is crucial to the ability of ICCs to generate slow waves, secretes this ion. ADP-ribosylation by cholera toxin leads to excessive activation of another channel for this ion, leading to its efflux into the intestinal lumen. ","answer":"ANSWER: chloride [or Cl-] <Biology> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 9/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 9 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] In this Dickens story, the title character tells the narrator about a spectre of a man holding his arm over his face that he has seen by a tunnel before three separate calamities. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Signal-Man” "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The supposed “first modern ghost story” is this pamphlet by Daniel Defoe, which purports to relate a real incident in which the title woman visited her friend Mrs. Bargrave a day after her death. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Apparition of Mrs. Veal [or A True Relation of the Apparition of one Mrs. Veal, the next Day after her Death: to one Mrs. Bargrave at Canterbury. The 8th of September, 1705] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The rationalist narrator camps out in a haunted house where phantoms snap the neck of his dog in this author’s story “The Haunted and the Haunters.” This writer used the words “It was a dark and stormy night” to open his novel Paul Clifford. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edward Bulwer-Lytton <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Name this Roman Catholic and Orthodox belief that the bodies of some saints, such as Bernadette, are not subject to decay. ","answer":"ANSWER: incorruptibility [accept any word forms, such as incorrupt or incorruptible] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Many saints with incorrupt bodies, such as Teresa of Avila, also exhibited this property in which they smell like flowers or perfume. Less excitingly, this term may refer to a state of grace rather than an actual aroma. ","answer":"ANSWER: odor of sanctity [or fragrant odors; or fragrance of sanctity; prompt on odors] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] As in the case of 20 th century saint Padre Pio, the odour of sanctity often emanates from these markings that resemble the wounds of Christ. ","answer":"ANSWER: stigmata <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Atellan Farce plays, which were performed in Rome, were slapstick shows that might have been performed in this language. The Tabula Bantina is one of the few written examples of this language of Southern Italy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Oscan "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] In 180 BCE, the leaders of this city in Southern Italy petitioned Rome to allow its language to officially be changed from Oscan to Latin. This first city to be founded in Magna Graecia was besieged by Hannibal during the Second Punic War and housed a notable Oracle of Apollo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cumae [or Kume; or Kumai; or Kuma; or Cuma] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Despite the prestige given to Greek, this orator related how he was criticized for once giving a speech in Greek in Sicily. He delivered the immortal line, \"When, O Catiline, do you mean to cease abusing our patience?\" ","answer":"ANSWER: Cicero [or Marcus Tullius Cicero] <European History> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 10/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 10 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Identify this action accomplished in 1819 when Kamehameha shared a symbolic meal with the women of his court, signaling that a period of “free eating” dubbed ʻAi Noa would not be reined in. ","answer":"ANSWER: abolition of the taboos [or abolition of kapu; or abolition of ai’ kapu; accept any answer indicating taboos or ai’ kapu and the idea of abolition] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] This man’s 1963 book Anthropology posits that the Hawaiians abolished the taboos because of “cultural fatigue.” He advanced the concept of “culture area” in his book Cultural and Natural Areas of Native North America and studied Ishi, the self-professed last member of the Yahi tribe. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alfred Kroeber [or Alfred Louis Kroeber] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The abolition of the taboos is ascribed to a power struggle between priestly and secular elites in this Czech-born Jewish anthropologist’s influential monograph Taboo, which was compiled in 1956 from his Oxford lecture notes. ","answer":"ANSWER: Franz Steiner [or Franz Baermann Steiner] <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Identify these people subject to earlier legislation like the Cubic Air Ordinance. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chinese-Americans [prompt to be less specific on Paper Sons] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Six years after passing the Cubic Air Ordinance, the San Francisco government passed a law making it illegal for prisoners to have this distinctive hairstyle of men during the Qing dynasty. ","answer":"ANSWER: queue [or cue; or pigtail; do not accept or prompt on \"ponytail\"] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] This California city lends its name to a \"method\" for quickly driving Chinese-Americans out of town. This largest city in the Redwood Empire region was once called the Queen City of the Ultimate West. ","answer":"ANSWER: Eureka <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Massive protests broke out in 2017 after what conservative politician defeated Salvador Nasralla, violating a constitutional ban on re-election to win a second term as president of Honduras? ","answer":"ANSWER: Juan Orlando Hernández (Alvarado) [or JOH] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The reelection of Hernández, along with the mounting drug- and gang-related violence, has led many Honduras to join these northward-bound groups who were vilified by Republican leaders around the 2018 US midterm elections. ","answer":"ANSWER: Central American migrant caravans [or Viacrucis del Migrante] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"6. ","answer":"ANSWER: San Pedro Sula <Current Events> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Give this term used for a yellow truck whose keys are the subject of a power struggle between the title ex-servant and the Smales family throughout a 1981 novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: the bakkie "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] This servant takes the keys to the bakkie in a Nadine Gordimer novel titled for his “people.” ","answer":"ANSWER: July "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Keys are also a motif in each of the short stories of this Nigerian-born author’s collection What is Not Yours is Not Yours. The title author is inspired by the strange muse Mary Foxe in her novel Mr. Fox. ","answer":"ANSWER: Helen Oyeyemi 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 11/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 11 <World Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Name this phenomenon that creates tiny rocks called LIVS when it interacts with ash. It is often accompanied by events called “dirty thunderstorms.” ","answer":"ANSWER: volcanic lightning [accept answers indicating lightning around volcanoes; prompt on lightning] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Many mechanisms that explain volcanic lightning suggest that it is caused by the formation of this solid substance in a caldera. This substance, solid ammonia, solid methane, and dry ice are formed from the the ejecta in cryovolcanoes. ","answer":"ANSWER: ice "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] This kind of eruption produced the first recorded observation of volcanic lightning. These ultra-powerful eruptions are characterized by rhyolitic flows and are even stronger than Pelean eruptions on the VEI scale. ","answer":"ANSWER: Plinian eruptions [accept ultra-Plinian eruptions; accept Vesuvian Eruptions] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] A temple complex in the district of Gaya (“GUY-uh”) in the present-day state of Bihar was built at the site of what religious object? ","answer":"ANSWER: the Bodhi tree [or descriptive answers indicating “the tree under which Buddha attained enlightenment”; accept the Mahabodhi Temple; accept Bodh Gaya] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The Mahabodhi temple complex includes two straight-sided examples of these typically receding, curvilinear towers that top many North Indian Hindu and Jain temples. They are capped off by ribbed stone disks called amalakas. ","answer":"ANSWER: shikhara "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] At Sanchi, reliefs showing Ashoka’s construction of the original Bodhi temple were carved into the southern gateway of the “Great” example of these hemispherical, dome-shaped Buddhist monuments. ","answer":"ANSWER: stupas <Other Fine Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Identify these events which include Austria's annual Licht ins Dunkel. The 2005 documentary The Kids Are All Right criticized the most popular American one, held each Labor Day. ","answer":"ANSWER: telethons [anti-prompt on Dodgerthon] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Jerry Lewis’s Labor Day telethon raised money to fight this disease, which comes in a form named for Duchenne. Mike Ervin, a former \"Jerry's Kid\" with this disease, criticized Lewis for his exploitation of people with disabilities. ","answer":"ANSWER: muscular dystrophy [or Duchenne muscular dystrophy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The annual telethon broadcast by Channel Seven in this city has attracted stars such as Whitney Houston and Stevie Wonder. A transcontinental railway completed in 1917 made this city less reliant on imports from its port of Fremantle. ","answer":"ANSWER: Perth, Western Australia <Other Academic> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 12/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 12 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Name this element which is also found in a catalyst for an asymmetric carbo-alumination reaction developed by Negishi called ZACA. ","answer":"ANSWER: zirconium "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"5. ","answer":"ANSWER: indenyl [accept indenyl effect; accept indene] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The indenyl effect applies to an associative form of this sort of reaction which a nucleophile can cause to occur through SN1 and SN2 mechanisms. ","answer":"ANSWER: substitution reaction <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Name this World War I campaign that began in 1915, a failed attempt by an Allied force under Sir Ian Hamilton to make an amphibious landing to clear the way for a naval capture of Constantinople. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gallipoli Campaign [or the Dardanelles Campaign; or the Battle of Canakkale] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"8. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles (Edwin) Bean "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Bean published an abridged version of his history partly titled for this 1918 battle. John Monash’s Australian Corps participated in the seven-mile Allied advance on the first day of this battle, which Erich Ludendorff called the “black day of the German army.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Battle of Amiens [or the Third Battle of Picardy] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Thomas Crow’s book Emulation profiles Jean Germain Drouais, Anne-Louis Girodet, and Jean Gros, who all underwent what formative professional experience, during which they developed their Neoclassical style? ","answer":"ANSWER: being trained by Jacques-Louis David [accept anything indicating that they were students of Jacques-Louis David; or they were pupils of Jacques-Louis David; or were part of the studio of Jacques-Louis David; or they belonged to the workshop of Jacques-Louis David] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Girodet helped paint a smaller copy of this canvas by David, which shows a father distributing swords to his three saluting sons. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Oath of the Horatii "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] David’s favorite pupil Drouais accompanied the older artist to this city, where he died mysteriously at age twenty-five. By painting Erasistratus Discovering the Cause of Antiochus' Disease, David himself won a funded residency in this city after three unsuccessful attempts. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rome, Italy [David struggled to win the Prix de Rome] <Painting and Sculpture> 4/18/2019 Emergency - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/169TBOYbIo4uTq3SOArITENxxxXEYpHzCgn5ar27Irjs/edit 13/13 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Emergency |Page 13 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] Identify this stylistic quirk shared by Bohumil Hrabal’s novel Dancing Lessons for the Advanced of Age and by approximately the last twenty pages of another novel, in which the narrator recalls being proposed to in Gibraltar. ","answer":"ANSWER: they’re written in one sentence [or obvious equivalents; prompt on written without paragraph breaks or similar] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] A man tells a bartender about his experiences reporting on the killing of the title animal in the Spanish region of Extremadura in this author’s single-sentence novella The Last Wolf. The World Goes On is a collection of stories by this winner of the 2015 Man Booker International. ","answer":"ANSWER: László Krasznahorkai "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Emergency","question":"[10] The sentence “And they marched all night” follows a 39,995 word sentence in The Gates of Paradise by this country’s author Jerzy Andrzejewski, who appears as “Alpha” in Czeslaw Milosz’s The Captive Mind. ","answer":"ANSWER: Poland <European Literature>"}]
